Marianna B. Medhurst

Email: mbmedhurst@gmail.com | Phone: 310.422.4837 | Tustin, CA 92780

LinkedIn: <u>mariannamedhurst</u> | Github: <u>mbmedhurst</u> | Portfolio: <u>mbmedhurst.com</u>

SUMMARY

A committed, enthusiastic and goal-oriented Full Stack Web Developer. Recent coding bootcamp graduate specializing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. Extensive experience working with business systems in various roles, including technical support, training, business analysis, writing user guides, usability and user acceptance testing. Highly skilled in managing multiple projects with changing priorities and schedules. A methodical approach to work with excellent interpersonal communication skills that assist in achieving business objectives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Node, Materialize, Material-UI, Moment.js., Firebase, GitHub, Postman, Jira, TFS

PROJECTS

#Adulting | GitHub | Deployed

Responsible for all of the styling throughout the app, created the graph component on the dashboard, coded and styled the component that dynamically adds avatars to the main menu.

An app for families to manage household chores

- Create chores and assign to family members, edit, mark as complete, delete if required
- Dashboard compares and displays progress for all family members
- Profile pages display stats for a single family member
- React (context & hooks), MongoDB, Passport, Material-UI, Chart.js, RandomColor (npm)

Google Books Search | GitHub | Deployed

Responsible for all coding and styling

An app to search for books on Google Books

- Search for books, view results, save to database, delete from database
- React, MongoDB, Google Books API, Material-UI

The Clicky Game | GitHub | Deployed

Responsible for all coding and styling

A memory game - try not to click on the same image twice

- Images shuffle after each click
- Top Score is remembered from game to game
- React, Material-UI, Shuffle-Array (npm)

EXPERIENCE

Software Quality Assurance Consultant - TenOTwo LLC - Tustin, CA

2014 - present

Freelance Quality Assurance, Usability and User Acceptance testing services for SaaS systems, websites and mobile apps. Create customized test scripts, evaluate apps for bugs and usability problems, evaluate text for

voice, style consistency and professionalism. Create training material and user documentation.

Key Accomplishments:

- Attended Nielsen Norman Group's Usability Week seminars: Analytics & User Experience, Human Mind & Usability, Measuring User Experience, Usability Testing & Usability Basic Training
- Took a number of Business Analysis courses through UCI's Department of Continuing Education

Business Validation & Training Manager - Achilles Group Ltd. - Oxford, UK

2010 - 2016

Managed the Business Validation team, which was responsible for planning and facilitating user acceptance testing of all new system enhancements with both internal and external customers. Liaised with product managers and developers to understand new functionality, wrote test scripts, set up test data, recruited participants from all parts of the business, facilitated test execution, collected and evaluated feedback, monitored progress of issue resolution, and reported results to stakeholders. Supervised the training program for all internal staff and VIP external customers on new and existing system functionality. This included in-person training, user-guides and e-learning material.

Key Accomplishments:

- Introduced a 'voice' style guide, which established a company-wide standard for all system text
- Known for our high standards and attention to detail, the team was frequently asked to write test cases for IT as well as participate in early rounds of system testing and defect re-testing

Application Manager, Maxim - Elsevier - Oxford, UK

2003 - 2010

Managed a \$200 million / year Commercial Sales billing system (Maxim). Provided daily technical support to 150 users worldwide, conducted scheduled and ad-hoc user training sessions at multiple worldwide locations, planned and facilitated annual user meetings and enhancement brainstorming sessions, created comprehensive system user guides, designed and maintained Maxim web site on company intranet.

Key Accomplishments:

- Worked closely with users in multiple departments and third party vendors to design and implement key system enhancements, resulting in greatly increased system functionality, more robust performance, greater accuracy in reporting, and compliance in at least three corporate regulatory obligations (Sarbanes-Oxley, PCI DSS, Tax)
- As Sarbanes-Oxley (Sox) Process Owner for Elsevier's worldwide Commercial Sales business, analyzed
 existing procedures within eleven user groups and designed new, customized workflows to incorporate
 Sox controls
- Oversaw and facilitated internal and external Sox audits with consistently excellent results

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Loyola Marymount University - Master of Arts, English

Loyola Marymount University – Bachelor of Arts, English